Guide to the J. E. Wallace Sterling Speeches
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
J. E. Wallace Sterling speeches
1949-1964
SC0557
Sterling, J. E. Wallace, (John Ewart Wallace), 1906-1985
0.5 Linear feet
Collection of President Sterling's speeches covering the years 1949 to 1964. Does not include every speech he made during those years. The format of the speeches includes typescripts, press releases, photocopies, and published versions.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Biographical/Historical note
J. E. Wallace Sterling was president of Stanford University from 1949 to 1968. During his 19 years in office, Stanford's endowment nearly doubled, the faculty increased 170 percent, graduate programs were improved, major building plans were completed, the Medical School was moved to campus from San Francisco, and the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center was built. After his retirement in 1968, Sterling was named University Chancellor.
Scope and Contents note
This collection of President Sterling's speeches covers the years 1949 to 1964 but does not include every speech he made during those years. The format of the speeches includes typescripts, press releases, photocopies, and published versions.
Arrangement note
The speeches are arranged chronologically.
Access Terms
Stanford University--Presidents.; Stanford University--Public Relations.
Collection Contents
- J. E. Wallace Sterling speeches, 1949-1964; Accession ARCH-1993-071
  - 1949-1958
    - A Lofty Purpose Shared. Inauguration Speech., 1949 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Stanford Commencement., 1954 Jun 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Goals of Stanford University., 1954 Dec 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Higher Education: Touchstone or Blarney Stone? American Iron & Steel Institute., 1957 Nov 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1958 Sep 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1959
    - Three Score and Fourteen Years Ago. Chamber of Commerce, Palo Alto, dinner., 1959 Feb 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Pasadena Rotary Club., 1959 Apr 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Annual Stanford Conference., 1959 May 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - “ Make Your Checks Payable To…” National Council on Community Foundations, San Francisco., 1959 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Freshman Convocation, 1959 Sep 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Meaning of Education. Westover School., 1959 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - What’s the Mind and What’s the Matter. Glass Containers Manufacturers Institute, Phoenix., 1959 Nov 12 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Reply by Sterling to questionnaire of November 27, 1959 from Fred M. Hechinger, education editor, New York Times. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1960
    - Stanford Today and Tomorrow. Student Assembly., 1960 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Changes and Chances. The Senior Lecture on Higher Education., 1960 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - An Educated Person. University of Southern California Commencement., 1960 Jun 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dedication of Stanford branch campus at Tours, France., 1960 Oct 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dedication of Stanford branch campus at Florence, Italy., 1960 Oct 12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1961
    - Stanford Today and Tomorrow., 1961 Jan 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles Dinner., 1961 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Junior Chamber of Commerce, Santa Monica. (2 copies), 1961 Jan 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Dr. Henry T. Heald, The Ford Foundation., 1961 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Notes for President Sterling. Stanford PACE Program Leadership Conference., 1961 Oct 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Today and Tomorrow. Assembly., 1961 Nov 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Conferences, 1961 Feb 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1962
    - Stanford Today and Tomorrow., 1962 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Trustees’ Dinner, Los Angeles (2 copies), 1962 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Greetings to the Class. Commencement Exercises. (2 copies), 1962 Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Address, Stanford PACE Program National Chairmen’s Conference., 1962 Sep 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Volunteer Recognition Day, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1963
    - Commencement, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Corporate Luncheon, San Francisco., 1963 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - National Telephone PACE Meeting, Chicago. Draft., 1963 Apr 24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1964
    - Address, Stanford Today and Tomorrow Convocation. (2 copies), 1964 Jan 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Undated
    - Statement by President Sterling for Smoke Signal news reel. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The University in the West Today. (Box 1, Folder 8)